Wealth is like seawater. The more you
drink the first year you become. There
will always be someone who hates what
you do, just hates the world and wants
to take it out on some person that they
see on YouTube. It's cultlike a lot of
the time that some of those crypto
communities out there are I think it's
destructive for the people who are part
of those cults. And I think it's
destructive for the space as well
because I think it makes us look like
[music] crazy.
>> Do not back down. Don't admit that
you're wrong. Never apologize.
>> [music]
>> That's how you build a strong cult
following.
>> They are absolutely mad on their
deathbed. No one will ever go, I wish I
wish I'd spent more time arguing with
people on the internet.
I am with Guy right now. I've been
watching his stuff for I think 5 years.
You have been an inspiration. Thank you
for coming on the show.
>> Thanks for having me, Bonnie.
>> It's um great to see you in real life.
[laughter]
>> Likewise. Likewise. It's always weird
when you when you meet someone that
you've seen on screen a lot because I
had this with with Ben Cowan just
yesterday. We met for the first time
>> and you guys do live all the time.
>> Yeah, we've been doing lives together
for about 3 years with with Rob from
Digital Asset News as well. I've met Rob
in person. I met Rob uh a few years ago
now, 2021, I think. Um, but yeah, Ben,
Ben Ben and I, we'd never met before.
And it's, you know, I know him pretty
well, I like to think. And you meet him
and it is there is that weird surreal
thing of being like, there he is in 3D,
you know? It's it's kind of strange.
>> There you are in 3D.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. We had a panel together earlier
and your stories are very interesting to
me, how you started and how you continue
being this number one channel in this
space. Do you want to maybe tell us the
story of why start a crypto channel?
>> Yeah, that's a good that's a good
question. I often ask myself that
sometimes. Why? Why am I doing this?
>> Yeah.
>> Um yeah, I mean I I remember when I
first heard about Bitcoin or when I
first became aware of it because you
know I think you tend to sort of think
back and it's like actually I'd probably
seen the word Bitcoin and probably seen
the symbol around but it hadn't
registered with me. Then one day, 2013,
I was living in East London and I walked
into a pub that was about 10 minutes
from uh from where I was living from the
flat and uh there was a sign behind the
bar saying uh we accept Bitcoin or
Bitcoin accepted here.
>> Wow.
>> And I was like that's interesting. So I
asked the uh I asked the barmaid about
it and she didn't really know but like
the landlord did or you know the guy who
was on supervising the shift did. So we
kind of talked about it and he sort of
gave an outline of what it was and I was
like that's that's interesting you know
that that is some that is worth digging
into a bit more. So as I recall I kind
of went and googled it when I got home
you know after a few drinks. So I was
you know not my not my shop. I mean it
was fascinating and like this was you
know what about 5 years after the
financial crash and that hit the UK
really hard. Obviously, it hit
everywhere hard and some places worse
than the UK, but you know, we were still
reeling from that. And I remember that
was a scary time. And I remember, you
know, there was talk that we were only a
few hours away from cash machines, from
ATMs running out. And I just thought
that had always kind of haunted me ever
since. And I'd become sort of more and
more kind of aware that, you know, this
money that we used on a day-to-day basis
just was was on such fragile
foundations. And then the more I learned
about Bitcoin, like the more I learned
about fiat money as well and like how,
you know, how bad it is. My preferred
method actually of of consuming
information is is reading. I'm quite
oldfashioned like that. But I noticed
that there was YouTube content out there
as well talking about Bitcoin. So, you
know, I started watching that and some
of it was some of it was really good.
You know, there these guys like, you
know, sort of really passionate and of
but quite often I found they were
talking at quite a high level,
>> right? And I always thought like, you
know, I'm not one of those people who
takes things in first time round. I
need, you know, I need time to think
about it. So that kind of, you know,
that sort of stuck in my head and then I
started sort of writing about it, not
really for any particular audience, but
mostly to get my thoughts in order about
it. And then that's when Nick and I were
introduced by a mutual friend, Nick, the
co-founder of Coinb with me. And um, he
has a background in Tradfi. He
understood implicitly a lot of the stuff
that I was still trying to figure out
myself. We started collaborating and
sort of publishing stuff and you know as
I said in the as I said in the panel we
had a website and uh we were pretty good
you know we were on page one of Google
for our particular you know for crypto
crypto education but then one day uh
Google's algorithm changed and we went
to page 8 or five or whatever it was you
know if you're not on page one you don't
exist so you know um and then we had an
all hands meeting and you know there
were about sort of five of us by this
point
>> and it was like well what are we going
to do do we do we rethink how we putting
out this content? Do we try and get back
onto page one? Do we produce more stuff?
What is it? And I said, well, I've been
watching quite a lot of YouTube videos,
so maybe we could try that. You know, we
could, it's kind of free to start a
YouTube channel. It kind of went from
there. Like, no one else was sort of
willing to present it. And so, because
it was my idea, and I, you know, I'd
done sort of bits of performing in the
past, you know, I'd done like plays and
stuff at university and stuff, so I
wasn't like, you know, completely
unfamiliar with uh with the concept of
performance. So I was like, "Okay, well
fine. We'll give it a go." I thought
back to a lot of those videos that I'd
watched and I, you know, I thought,
well, they were doing some things well,
they were doing some things right, but a
lot of it I thought we could do better.
So that was the and that was always the
aim. And what we wanted to do from the
start was try and make it simple for
someone who'd been in my position who
just heard about Bitcoin, who just heard
about crypto, and I just knew that if
they clicked on a video and it was
straight away blockchain this and
consensus mechanism this and proof of
work that they, you know, you you'd lose
people. So we tried to talk about it in
sort of simple terms that we thought
everyone could understand or you know
most people could understand and just
start from where we started or start
from where I started in particular
knowing nothing. Um so that was always
the goal and just to sort of we wanted
to kind of turn the sort of
professionalism dial a bit. I mean our
early videos are just so bad from a
quality perspective. You know I think I
think the information was great but we
were learning as we went right.
>> Um but you know the production quality
was terrible because we didn't really
have much money. Mhm.
>> Um, and we didn't have sort of proper
camera studio set up and stuff. So, I
used to shoot it in a friend of mine's
living room
>> and you know it was really really
amateur. Um, but you know, we learned as
we went all the time. We're sort of
learning more about crypto but also
learning more about the business of
content creation. Those two processes
advanced in tandem. So, but we always
tried to we always try to keep it to
that philosophy of like you know someone
is coming to this for the first time.
this is the opportunity to get them and
keep them interested and get them, you
know, passionate about this space. And I
think we I think we achieved that. You
know, a lot of people people still come
up to me and say, "Oh, I got into I got
into crypto by watching your videos or
your videos really helped me, you know,
learn about it and things like that."
And it's it's amazing because that's
that's what we wanted to do. and all the
other stuff about it becoming a business
and you know a sort of wider platform
that all came later but it just stemmed
from that that thing of like crypto is
amazing let's talk about it and see
where it goes
>> during co I think I started the channel
because it is so difficult and
complicated and mostly in English and it
was very hard for me to you know explain
to my mom what I learned today
>> so Then I started this channel thinking
that if I push myself and force myself
to study this and translate and you have
to really digest.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So you really have to understand
what you're saying
>> and I al also keep in mind that you know
some of my audience might be a first
time newbie
>> and that's that's why I keep the
language very simple. But here's the
problem. So after a while your audience
grow with you. Now they aren't very
aware of what PPOS is and all the terms.
If you oversimplify these things, it
gets boring for them. So how do you find
that balance?
>> Yeah, that's difficult because that's
something that we still think about to
this day. You know, we're still looking,
>> okay, people are not coming to crypto in
anything like the volumes that they did
in 2017, in 2021 or whatever it is, but
they're still coming and we still want
to be the gateway for those people. So,
and I I I think that's something to
think about. You know, our content
strategy is quite often geared to that.
It's like, well, do we want to make a
video that is going to get 100,000 views
straight out the gates and then within a
week it's kind of the topic is no longer
particularly relevant and people have
moved on to another video or, you know,
another channel or whatever. um or do we
want to do we want to make something
that it might only get a few thousand
views in the first couple of weeks but
just grows and grows and grows. And I
think that's been one of the reasons why
we've continued to to grow and continued
to get subscribers is because we're not
afraid to make that introduction to
Bitcoin video or how to use a crypto
wallet video or you know that evergreen
stuff. We've we've tried to focus a lot
on evergreen and you know you have to
balance it. Sometimes you have to react
to what's happening in the moment. You
have to give people the information that
they need right then.
>> But I like to think that we've built a
big foundation of stuff that you know
someone might be coming to still in
three or four years time you know in the
next cycle um and going ah bitcoin I
need to understand okay okay this video
was made four years ago but it's still
you know it's still as relevant as it
ever was. So I think it is possible to
to balance that.
>> Have you ever been frustrated looking at
your comment section? I have noticed
that, you know, since the market isn't
that great, people are getting
frustrated
>> and they take it out on you. They're
like, "Bitcoin? What Bitcoin?"
>> Yeah.
>> What how do you deal with that?
>> It can be difficult because I don't say
I don't read the comments. I mean, I
don't read all of them, but [snorts] I
will I I generally look because often
there is, you know, constructive stuff
in there and it is good to know how
people feel,
>> right? But yeah, it is frustrating and
you do develop a bit of a a thick skin
after. I mean, you have to and that and
and that's that goes for whatever sort
of content you're making. You know, it's
crypto content or gardening content,
whatever. There will always be someone
who hates what you do or hates you or
hates, you know, just hates the world
and wants to take it out on some person
that they see on YouTube. I often like
to think that if someone's leaving a
negative comment,
>> that's a victory for me. you know, if
it's, you know, if it's about me or if
it's about the channel, whatever. I try
to see that as a victory because they've
taken time out of their lives to to to
vent that. And the only loser there is
is them. That said, you know,
constructive criticism is great. It's
fine to disagree, you know, and you
know, it shouldn't it, as Ben said
during our panel, we don't want to live
in an echo chamber. Um, but yeah, when
someone's when someone's abusive or
whatever, it is sort of I I try to see
it as a reflection on them and not me. I
think the most I I tell you what the
most frustrating thing about the comment
section has always been for me is that
there are communities out there who are
utterly deranged. Do you know what I
mean? There like there are crypto
communities who are wedded to one
particular blockchain or one particular
you know figure or things like that and
they they will not hear any criticism at
all. They are absolutely mad,
>> but they come to you and
>> this is the thing like they hate us
because you know we might have said
something honest or negative about them
in the past
>> but they will still come and they'll be
like you said this and it's incorrect or
you said that you hate this project or
whatever. And I don't know, I it it
annoys me because
it's just it it's cultlike a lot of the
time that some of those crypto
communities out there are if they're not
cults, they're pretty close. And I think
that's really destructive. I think it's
destructive for the people who are part
of those cults. And I think it's
destructive for the space as well
because I think it makes us look like it
makes us look crazy a lot of the time.
And at the end of the day, [laughter]
um, there's a there's a guy on, uh,
there's a guy on on Twitter who posts
as, uh, Guart. I don't know if you've
ever and he's got a podcast as well.
He's good. He's very smart guy, very
funny, very witty. And he posted not so
long ago. He put something along the
lines of like in in the future people
will look back and wonder how on earth
it was that we fought each other to you
know to the death over what is
essentially back office software. Do you
know that's always stuck with me because
it's like okay you know this stuff is
fascinating it is it is you know it is
changing the the financial landscape. is
changing the world but at the end of the
day it's software and you know people
are people lose their minds over it. I I
think passion is great. I I love it that
people are engaged with it and engaged
with the mission of crypto and and and
and are fascinated by the technology and
what I can and what it what it can do
for them. But um yeah to see how to see
how crazy they get about it sometimes
it's just like chill out touch grass you
know.
>> I love that. Yeah, it's it's crazy.
>> But sometimes people give me advice.
They're like, "You really need to have a
very strong opinion. Do not back down.
Don't admit that you're wrong. Never
apologize. That's how you build a strong
cult following." And I'm just like, I
can't do that.
>> Do you want do I mean, do you want a
cult following? Like that is, you know,
I think it's it's one of those things
you think, oh, it'd be great if people
worshiped the Grand [laughter] Hooked on
something. No, it's terrible. Like it's
crazy. You want people to you want
people to engage with you and listen to
what you've got to say, but like you
know do you want to be an object of of
of devotion for them or whatever? Like
100% no. Like [laughter]
it's just like I think anyone you know
you can't human beings are very uh
strange and wonderful in that regard.
you know, we do form
not always rational attachments to
people and things and ideas and and
philosophies, but I really think it's
important at the end of the day, you
know, to to have to have the perspective
to be able to let go of that. And it's
like it's just a person on YouTube. It's
just some English dude who is talking
about about technology. It's like don't
attach too much importance to it. you
know you and your and your family and
your life are more important than this.
>> Yes.
>> Um so you know I love it. I love it that
people are engaged and passionate but I
think it's perspective is so important.
>> Earlier I think in the panel you
mentioned something about we are all
going to die or our time is limited.
remember.
>> So yeah, um one of my one of my mantras,
one of one of the one of the um uh
pieces of wisdom if you like that I live
my life by is that on their deathbed
>> no one will ever go I wish I wish I'd
spent more time arguing with people on
the internet. Like
I wish I'd traveled more. I wish I'd I
wish I'd met more people. I wish I'd had
more children. Whatever it is, it'll
never be that. It'll ne and and I mean,
I I consider myself to be a little bit
old-fashioned like this, but I am
constantly amazed by how some people can
literally spend hours of every precious
day that they have on this beautiful
planet of ours arguing with a stranger
in another country over something that
most the time is totally trivial. I
really do feel it's like, you know, we
are on Earth for such a short period of
time. Sure, you know, stand [snorts]
your ground and defend what is defend
what is important to you. And like it's
not to say that argument isn't isn't
isn't a great way of of communicating
and and working out our differences and
working out how we feel about things,
but at the end of the day, like, you
know, it's not the most important thing.
But some for some people, it seems to be
their whole life, you know, which is
which is crazy. Some some some of the
creators build their brand off
>> arguing with people. Yeah.
>> Because that's how you get all the
eyeballs and stuff.
>> Yeah.
>> So, you could call that a strategy.
>> And um what you just mentioned earlier
could apply to I think most things in
life.
>> Yeah.
>> Why are you so sad over losing one
project or why are you sad about this
interview not going well? Like these are
all very small things.
>> Yeah. But then if I expand that, then I
won't be doing anything but just to hang
out.
>> Yeah. I think it's really important like
to, you know, to to feel like, well,
what do you want? Do you want millions
of people engaging with what you're
saying and getting angry about it and
stoking all that hate? Or wouldn't it be
wouldn't it be much better to just have
a small community of people who are
engaged with what you say, who aren't
you who aren't there for drama or
whatever like that? I think, you know, I
think we confuse, you sometimes confuse
big numbers with happiness. And
actually, I think so many people try so
hard to to please everyone or to attract
the largest number of people to their
views or their platform and they kind of
lose sight of the the bigger picture.
You know, we can only we can only please
so many people. Is it true that after
you reach a number or a target in wealth
or in subscription whatever that number
is you stop becoming happier like that
there is a cap for everything? H
well someone said that can't remember
what the figure is but I think certainly
in the states it was proved that if you
got above a certain level of wealth or I
think it I mean this was a while ago it
doesn't apply anymore because of
inflation but I think someone said like
>> $100,000 a year a while ago used to be
the level like once you got there every
you know life was pretty comfortable but
to in order to make your life better
measurably better you'd have to get to
like a million you the next the next
leap would be so big. And I always
remember something I think it was um
Arthur Schopenhau said I think it was
him. He said wealth is like sea water.
The more you drink the thirstier you
become. And the same is true of fame.
And it it is true like you you I think
again we attach importance to numbers.
You know we attach importance to kind of
what essentially arbitrary numbers. I'll
be happy if I have a million dollars.
and then you get a million dollars and
you're like actually I think I'd be
happier if I had 10 million. [laughter]
So, but you if if you've got any sort of
self-awareness, you'll know that if you
get to $10 million, then it'll be 50
$100 million. And there are so many
people out there who I think just drive
themselves into the ground because
they're chasing an arbitrary number in
their bank account or an arbitrary
number of followers or views or
engagement or anything like that. And I
think, yeah, but beyond a certain point,
you just I think you have to be you have
to accept that if you're happy and in
your, you know, moisturized in your
lane, then then that's what you should
stick at. I I think I I'm I'm always
wary of people who just sort of keep
pushing on for some for some number that
ultimately is kind of meaningless.
>> What makes you happy? Small things.
>> Small things. My wife.
>> Nice. A
>> I have to say that. [laughter]
>> Oh, you have to.
>> I have to say that. But it is true. It
is true. Um, uh, I love, uh, I love the
mornings. I wake up really early. I wake
up at about 5 and I love the quiet in
the mornings before anyone else is up
when I feel generally sort of quite
alert. And I get my I get most of my
best work done at that point. And uh,
yeah, I love I love being outdoors. I
love having a good book to read. You
know, I'm fairly sort of simple to I'm
quite easy to please really. It's more
like your family and your private life
instead of the success.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I think success you know if
if if you can say that we achieve that
is you know it it is helpful for sort of
validating yourself and you know for
feeling that you've made a difference
and again it goes back to this idea
we're on we're on earth for such a short
amount of time you don't want to feel
like you've wasted it. If the one thing
I've I've found from having a, you know,
having a relatively sort of successful
channel in this industry and working
with so many good people is that really
it's it's it's all about what that
success allows you to do. And it's the
same with wealth, I think. Like it, you
know, if it allows you to spend more
time with the people you you love doing
the things that you love, then then it's
worth it. But again, you know, you can
keep striving for a huge number, but it
won't change. You know, you won't if
you're if you're uh if you've got a $100
million in the bank, it doesn't buy you
any more time with your family.
>> Someone will say you're shopping at the
wrong place.
>> Yes. Exactly. Exactly. [laughter]
>> Yeah. You're Yeah. You just need to you
just need to adjust your perspective.
But yeah, I mean, do you find that, you
know, how do you do you find yourself
attaching sort of importance to kind of
to particular milestones or particular
numbers? I thought I would, but every
time I reach that, I'm just like, well,
okay, this is just a number, right? And
oftentimes I do think about what really
makes me happy. It's all the little
moments playing with my dog or, you
know, hanging out with my family and,
>> you know, talking
>> about whatever with my friends.
>> So, those are the little moments, but
then, you know, you're still trying to
look for that balance. You can't be
messing around all day because there's
still, you know, work and important
mission to do.
>> So,
>> I love that you're sharing this with us.
This is
>> and you are so warm in person. Honestly,
there is like this very
>> likewise
>> very genuine personality that
is the same we see on screen. And thank
you for sharing that.
>> It's a pleasure. It's a pleasure. Well,
thank you for giving me the opportunity
to talk about myself [laughter]
because it's one of my favorite topics.
But um no, it's nice and and like look,
you know, it's it's it's always nice
when you meet someone like you or Ben um
who is kind of the same on camera as
they are or in real life as they are on
camera because like I think that's you
know we live in we live in a very
artificial age where you know a lot of
people aren't what they claim to be.
they rent the same sports car and then
we share we post this, you know, we're
so successful.
>> But
>> I Yeah, I think it's our it's the duty
of us regular people to try and push
back against that sort of stuff because
it is just nonsense. But yeah, it's
lovely to um it's lovely to have a nice
chat like this, not not all about crypto
as well.
>> Yeah, this is very humane. [laughter]
>> Thank you guys.
>> Thank you, Bonnie.